JOHN J. SCHIAVO

(209)768-8166 ~ PO Box 291, Jamestown, California 95327 ~ JSchiavoCPA@att.net

PROFILE

An accounting professional with seven year's success assisting small businesses. My experience and ability to quickly learn new topics has allowed me to develop a broad foundation in accounting and financial analysis. In addition, I have an understanding of relational database concepts and statistical modeling. I believe ideal work efficiency is obtained by emphasizing work *quality* and by seeking constant improvement in my methods and processes.

HIGHLIGHTS

- ✓ Licensed CPA (California)
- ✓ Supervisory experience
- ✓ Analytical and detail-oriented

- ✓ Business process analysis
- ✓ Data analysis/SQL/Advanced Excel
- ✓ Custom report writing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Controller, Kinematic Automation, Inc., Sonora, California

February 2009 - Present

- Manage G/L accounting and reviews all journal entries prepared by other staff
- · Calculate deferred revenue, performs month-end closing and prepares monthly financial figures to CFO
- Oversee cost accounting in a job-cost environment, from single parts to complex custom systems
- Manage calculation and reporting of Federal export tax credits, coordinates with outside advisor
- Organize periodic inventory counts, evaluates results, and performs adjustments to items costs, as needed
- Advise IT engineer on technical requirements of auxiliary financial reporting tool
- Train co-workers on ERP system, business software applications, and accounting topics
- Revised sales tax reporting processes to improve accuracy and simultaneously achieving time savings
- Identified and corrected overstatement of inventory resulting in achieved reductions of over \$100,000
- Organized "Employee Benefit Fund" to assist employees and employees' families through hardship

Assistant Controller, Alternative Energy Designs, Inc., Sonora, California August 2008 – January 2009

- Managed G/L accounting, tax accounting, financial reporting, accounts payable, and fixed assets
- Prepared weekly cash-flow reporting for Controller to aid in evaluation of working capital
- Migrated existing qualified pension plan to new financial adviser and third-party administrator
- Processed payroll in a back-up capacity during absence of regular payroll administrator
- Claimed previously unclaimed energy-efficiency tax credits resulting in refunds of thousands of dollars

Staff Accountant, Aalfs, Evans & Company, LLP, Eureka, California

January 2005 – July 2008

- Prepared tax returns, including Schedules E, for individuals and trusts with multi-unit portfolios
- Assisted payroll department with payroll preparation and review and quarterly filings
- Prepared tax-basis financial statements under accrual and cash methods of accounting
- Successfully led team of six preparers responsible for Firm's business property statement filings
- Managed in-house database tracking clients' business property statement filings

EDUCATION

B.S., Business Administration Major, Humboldt State University, Arcata, California

2006

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Aviation Electronics Technician, United States Navy

June 1999 – October 2003

- Intermediate-level troubleshooting and repair of analog and digital aviation electrical components
- Supervised night shift of transmitter technicians and trained junior sailors on test equipment

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Judge – Sonora Union High School Senior Exit Projects

Member – Finance sub-committee of the Sierra Waldorf School Board

Coach – Tuolumne County Youth Soccer

May 2009 – Present Dec. 2008 – Sept. 2010 2010 & 2011 Seasons